# **Ümit YAMAN**

# Fullstack Web Developer | POWERCODERS PARTICIPANT



## **PROFILE**

I worked as a military prosecutor in Turkey. After coming to Switzerland, I planned a new career and attended courses in IT. I am looking forward to a job position where I can show my IT skills. I believe I am an ideal candidate especially for positions that require being a team player. I am a positive, cheerful and friendly person.

## CONTACT

di.01.1991



umit.yaman@powercoders.org



+41787213137



Bireggstrasse 1, 6003, Lucerne



**Portfolio** 

**GitHub** 

TURKEY (PERMIT-B)

## **LANGUAGES**

Turkish **Mother Tongue** Zazaki **Mother Tongue** 

German C1 English B2

## **REFERENCES**

#### **Hany WASSEF**

Lead Company Relations, Powercoders hany.wassef@powercoders.org +41 77 992 84 58

## **HOBBIES**

#### Reading

I read novels from classic world literature and poetry from Turkish literature every day.

## **Swimming**

I often swim in the lakes and rivers in Lucerne.

## Hiking

I hike with a group in different mountains in Switzerland.

## **IT SKILLS**

Advanced HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript React, Git & Github, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Intermediate

Postman, MySQL, Rest Api, Figma

**Beginner AWS Cloud** 

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

01.2014 - 07.2016

## Military Prosecutor - Turkish Navy, Kocaeli, Turkey

As a military prosecutor, I conducted several investigations

06.2013 - 12.2013

## Intern - Justice Academy and Courts, Ankara, Turkey

I worked as a trainee in various military, civil and high courts and I attended lectures at the justice academy

11.2012 - 03.2013

#### Intern - Turkish Naval Forces, Yalova, Turkey

I attend the basic officer training course in the Turkish Naval Forces

#### **EDUCATION**

03.2023 - 06.2023

#### Powercoders Bootcamp - ICT Work Integration Program, Bern

- Foundations in HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Weekly business & social skills training (team work, communication, etc.)

05.2022 - 06.2023

#### HiCoders - Full Stack Web Developer, Zürich

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git & Github, Responsive Design, Bootstrap, React, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MySQL

09.2019 - 06.2020, 09.2021 - 06.2022

#### University of Lucerne, Lucerne, Switzerland

I attended law lectures as a guest student

09.2015 - 07.2016

# Master's degree in international war crimes - Kocaeli University, Kocaeli, Turkey

I could not continue with my thesis due to political restrictions

09.2014 - 07.2016

## Bachelor's degree in international relations - Anadolu University, Eskisehir, Turkev

I could not continue from the fifth semester due to political restrictions

09.2008 - 09.2012

## Bachelor's degree in law - Kocaeli University, Kocaeli, Turkey

I graduated from law school

# **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

11.21 - PRESENT

#### **Swiss Volunteers**

I am a member of Swiss Volunteers

10.22 - PRESENT

Volunteer - Katholische Kirche St. Theodul, Littau, Switzerland

I take part in the distribution of food collected to be given to people in need.

# **COURSES AND CERTIFICATES**

# **University of Michigan & Coursera**

- Introduction to HTML5
- Introduction to CSS3
- Advanced Styling with Responsive Design